<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-US"><title>Aidan Naveja</title><id>https://blog.naveja.us/</id><author><name>Aidan Naveja</name><uri>https://blog.naveja.us/</uri></author><generator>Hugo gohugo.io</generator><rights>Copyright © 2022, Aidan Naveja.</rights><updated>2024-10-22T07:43:12Z</updated><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.naveja.us/blog/" hreflang="en-US"/><entry><title>My initial experience with Netlify &amp; Hugo</title><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://blog.naveja.us/initial-netlify-experience/"/><id>https://blog.naveja.us/initial-netlify-experience/</id><updated>2024-10-14T00:00:00Z</updated><published>2024-10-14T00:00:00Z</published><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="netlify--hugo">Netlify &amp;amp; Hugo&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I liked the look/function of &lt;a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bear Blog&lt;/a>, but wanted to be able to write in markdown and liked the idea of using GitHub to manage/host the files. I had had difficulties with GitHub Pages in the past, so I thought I would try out Netlify after I learned about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It took a bit of time to trouble shoot things as I was trying to get &lt;a href="https://github.com/janraasch/hugo-bearblog">hugo-bearblog&lt;/a> to work with the Netlify + Hugo Quickstart template. That was a deadend no matter how many different aveneues I attempted. Eventually I just created an empty GitHub repo via the web interface, cloned it to my local machine, initialized a hugo site in the git directory, added hugo-bearblog as a git submodule, and copied over the contents of the example site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I pushed that back to the git repo and Netlify quickly built and hosted the website. After confirming it worked, I swapped the example content for a barebones version of my own. I plan to expand on most parts of the website ASAP, but need to take a break as I have spent a decent amount of time getting this to build on Netlify.&lt;/p></content></entry></feed>